I've made another version of the World Bank data dashboard and this time,
我制作了世界银行数据仪表板的另一个版本
I've used the API on the backend to get the data.
这次是在后端使用 API 来获取数据
You'll also notice that there's a new red button.
你还会注意到 多了一个新的红色按钮
This is actually a menu where I've created a filter,
这实际上是一个菜单 是我创建的一个过滤器
where you can choose certain countries and
你可以在其中选择特定的国家并提交
submit and then it will filter out for just the countries that you've chosen.
然后它将仅返回你所筛选的国家数据
The reason why I have added this extra feature,
添加这项额外功能的原因是
is just in case you already know a little bit about web development.
可能你已经对 Web 开发有所了解
I'm trying to encourage you to add extra features if you want to
我想鼓励你添加更多功能
and it also might help you understand a little bit,
这还可以帮助你了解
how the code works with the API on the backend.
后端代码与 API 协作的一些原理
So what I'm gonna do is I'm going to show you
我要做的就是演示
the code behind this version of the web app.
Web 应用这个版本的代码
So that you can see how it works and how I've used
这样你就可以了解其工作原理以及
the API to pull the data instead of using a CSV file.
使用 API 而不是 CSV 文件 提取数据的方式
So here on the left you can see all of the files that make up
在左侧 可以看到组成该版本应用的所有文件
this on GitHub so that you can download and take a look at it.
我也将其放在了 GitHub 上 方便你下载查看
The only files that have changed is this data.py
唯一修改的文件是这个 data.py
file which is inside of scripts and that's where I'm doing all the data wrangling.
该文件位于 scripts 文件夹 这就是我进行所有数据整理的地方
Then there's index.html where I've added the code,
然后是 index.html 我在其中添加了代码
that takes care of the red filter menu and then I've had to add
处理红色的过滤器菜单 然后我必须
a little bit of extra code into rootstock.py
在 routes.py 中添加一些额外的代码
to take care of the logic for all of the filtering.
来完成筛选的逻辑
So let's start with the data wrangling and data.py.
我们从数据整理和 data.py 开始
Don't worry too much yet about how the red filter works on the front end.
暂时还不必太担心红色过滤器在前端如何工作
I'm just going to show you what the API.
我先演示一下 API 数据整理代码的工作
So I'm starting out with this country default dictionary,
从这个 country_default 字典开始
where I have the country name and the three character ISO codes.
其中有国家名称和三个字符的 ISO 编码
Before in earlier videos I used the two character ISO codes.
在之前的视频中 我使用了两个字符的 ISO 编码
In this code I actually use the three-character ISO codes,
在这段代码中 我实际上使用了三个字符的 ISO 代码
but either way works with the API.
但无论哪种方式都对该 API 适用
So here I have my return figures function like before and
这里 像之前一样有 return_figures 函数
the difference now is that I'm inputting this list of countries.
现在的区别是 我输入的是这个国家列表
So it's the countries that I'm filtering for and by default I want
这就是我要筛选的国家 默认情况下
all the countries. So let's scroll down.
是所有国家 向下滚动
This logic here says that just in case there's no country's variable sent over
这里的逻辑是说 万一没有传入国家变量
my country default the country's variable and then I do a little bit of preparation here,
则将 countries 变量设置为默认值 然后在这里做了一些准备工作
where I make a list of the countries with the semicolon between
每个国家名称之间用分号分隔 因为这就是 API 在 URL 中的预期格式
Then here I'm making a list of indicators that I want to grab because I'm going to
然后这里将要获取的指标 创建了一个列表存储
iterate through them in a for loop and make all of the visualizations one at a time.
因为我想使用 for 循环进行遍历 一次性处理所有可视化
So moving down a little bit,
往下移一点
here's where I iterate through each indicator.
这是遍历指标的地方
So the first step is to get the URL string ready to send over to the World Bank API.
第一步是准备好 URL 字符串 用来发送给世界银行 API
Then I use the Request library down here in line 54
在下面的第 54 行代码中使用 requests 库
to get the URL and then I receive the data back in Json.
获取 URL 然后收到 JSON 格式的数据
Here in line 59,
第 59 行代码
I'm iterating through the data that I got back from
遍历从 API 获得的数据
the World Bank API and getting it ready for plotly.
为 plotly 的使用做准备
So that is the end of the foreloop so going back
这就是 for 循环结束的地方
up what happens is that it goes to the next indicator,
再次回去 接下来处理的就是下一个指标
prepares the URL and then gets the data and
准备 URL 然后获取数据
then puts it in a dataframe and appends it to this data frames variable in line 63.
将其放入一个 dataframe 在第 63 行代码追加到这个 data_frames 变量中
So that I'm getting all the data prepared.
这样我就可以将所有数据准备好了
Once the data is ready,
数据准备好后
I go and prepare each graph,
再准备每个图表
each visualization one at a time,
每次绘制一个可视化
just like before and the other version of the code.
就像之前版本的代码一样
So here I'm preparing graph one there is still some data wrangling I have to
在这准备 graph_one 仍然有一些数据整理工作
do some sorting to make sure that everything's in the right order that I want.
我要做一些排序 确保按照想要的正确顺序进行绘制
I get the country list just like I did before and the other version of
获取国家列表 像之前的版本一样
my app and here I'm preparing graph one for plotly.
这里是为 plotly 准备好 graph_one
Then I have the layout here as well.
这里也同样有布局的设置
Then I'm preparing graph two with the second dataframe that I created and
然后 使用创建的第二个 dataframe 准备 graph_two
again there's a little bit of data wrangling
同样有一些数据整理操作
and then I prepare graph two and layout for two,
然后准备 graph_two 和 layout_two
graph three scrolling down graph
graph_three 继续向下 graph_four
four and then I append all the charts and my function returns all of the figures.
然后追加所有图表 函数返回所有图表
So the major difference here in this data.py file is
因此 data.py 文件的主要区别是
that I'm using the API to get the data instead of using CSV files,
我使用了 API 获取数据 而不是之前上传的 CSV 文件
Next let's look at index.html.
接下来看一下 index.html
So index.html is very similar to what it looked like before.
index.html 与之前看起来非常相似
The only difference is that I've added a collapsible filter,
唯一的区别是我添加了一个可折叠的过滤器
which in reality is just an HTML form that you can submit.
本质上是一个可以提交的 HTML 表单
So I didn't show you how to make a form
我之前没有讲过 如何制作表单
before or how to submit a form and how all of that logic works,
如何提交表单 以及这些逻辑如何运作
but I'll walk you through the code
但我稍后会带你浏览代码
a little bit just so you have an idea of what's going on.
使你对这些内容有所了解
It's a little bit beyond the scope of this course,
这稍微超出了本课程的大纲
but it shows you that if you really like doing this web development stuff,
但是如果你真的喜欢做这些 Web 开发工作
that there's more to learn and more to do and you can keep adding more features.
这会让你知道 还有更多的东西要学习 你可以添加更多的功能
So scrolling down, here I have drop-down menu for filter.
向下滚动 这里是用于过滤器的下拉菜单
So all of this came from an example on the Bootstrap website and so
所有这些都来自 Bootstrap 网站上的示例
I have a button here which is the red button and then I have a drop
这里有一个按钮 是红色按钮 然后有一个下拉菜单
down menu and you can see here I'm using Ginger,
你会看到这里使用了 Jinja
which I'll explain in a minute what I'm doing and then there's
一会儿我会解释其作用
a form and so then this form can actually be submitted,
这里是表单 这个表单实际上可以提交
with this submit button down here.
通过点击此处的 submit 按钮
So what does all of this Ginger code doing.
那么这些 Jinja 代码在做什么?
Essentially. I'm getting from the front-end which
基本上 我从前端得到
variables were selected or submitted and I
那些被选中被提交的变量
am doing some filtering so that I know which ones should be checked
做一些过滤 以便我知道如何根据之前提交的内容
based on what were submitted before
显示哪些需要被选中
and here I'm populating the names of all the countries.
这里是填充所有国家的名称
So maybe a little bit confusing if you're not too
如果你对 JavaScript Jinja 和 HTML 不太熟悉 可能会有些混乱
But look at the code for a bit and see if you can figure it out.
但是请再阅读一下代码 看看是否可以理解
The other key to this code is down here,
这个代码的另一个关键之处在下面这里
there's a little bit of JavaScript that I've written
我写了一些 JavaScript
actually Jquery to take care of the filter.
实际上是 jQuery 负责过滤器的功能
So for example you can see here that
比如 你可以在这里看到
this checks or unchecks the filter box is based on the Select All box.
会根据 Select All 框来选中或取消选中框
So if you go back here and you hit Select All,
如果返回这里 点击 Select All
that's what this is taken care of uncheck Select All box when
这就是代码对应的功能 取消选中某个框的时候
unchecking another box so that's here when I click
会将 Select All 的框也取消选中 所以在这里
on something it unchecks the Select All box and then
我点击一些框 会取消选中 Select All 框
checks Select All when rechecking all the other boxes which you just saw.
重新选中其他所有框时 Select All 也会被选中 就像你刚才看到的
When I recheck everything Select All gets chosen.
当重新选中所有框时 Select All 也被选中了
So the other part to look at is rootstock.py and rootstock.py is very similar in
还有一部分是 routes.py 而 routes.py 实际上是非常相似的
fact if you look from here down it should look quite similar to what we had before.
如果从这里往下看 应该看起来和之前非常相似
The difference is now roots.py He has to take care of submitting this form.
现在的区别是 routes.py 必须负责提交这个表单
So what happens is when you submit the form it sends out something called a
提交表单时 它会发送一个 POST 请求
request a post request and so when you send out this post request.
当你发送 POST 请求时
I'm saying hey read this form and figure out which countries were
代码就说 来读取这个表单 找出哪些国家被选中了
selected and then for each country that was selected appended to this list.
将每个被选中的国家添加到这个 countries_selected 列表中
Countries selected and then you can see here countries selected is sent to the front end
然后你可以在此处看到 countries_selected 被发送到了前端的 index.html
at index.html and that's what a lot of the Ginger code in index.html was doing.
这就是 index.html 中许多 Jinja 代码使用的
It was iterating through this country's selected variable,
遍历这个 countries_selected 变量
so that it knew which check box should be
这样它就能根据过滤器 知道应该选中哪个框不应该选中哪个框
So I know I'm kind of going through this quickly but I think if you download
我知道这次浏览代码有点太快了 但是如果你将这些代码自己下载下来
this code yourself and take the time to look at it and figure out all the logic.
花时间阅读 弄清楚其中的逻辑
It'll be really helpful for just seeing what you can do with a web app.
会帮助你了解在一个 Web 应用中可以实现什么功能
But the main thing to think about,
但主要需要考虑的是
if you're doing the advanced version of the project,
如果你想要完成项目的进阶版本
is what's happening in data.py
是 data.py 中的功能
the filter thing here is really just extra and extra thing I made.
这里的过滤器实际上只是一个多余的额外功能
But the main point is looking at how I've used the API
重点是看我如何使用 API
in data.py to get the data and then use it to make the plots.
在 data.py 中获取数据 进行绘图